ServerScout AI Risk Briefing Assistant is an AI-assisted security reporting workflow.
It helps small teams understand scan results quickly.
This demo uses the verified local build and the packaged prototype.
Small teams often receive technical scan data.
They still need a clear answer about what should be fixed first.
They also need to explain why the risk matters to stakeholders.
ServerScout includes dashboard, asset management, scan tasks, vulnerability management, topology, attack surface visualization, external intelligence, report export, and the new AI Briefing page.
The integrated AI Briefing page takes scan evidence and generates a readable risk brief.
Click Generate AI Brief.
The output provides an executive summary.
It also provides remediation priorities and report-ready language.
The AI layer does not replace scanning.
It helps users translate scan data into decisions.
Those decisions include what is urgent, why it matters, and what should be written in the report.
This is useful for small businesses, internal IT teams, freelance security testers, and junior security engineers.
The business model starts with free local use, then grows into team subscriptions, per-report pricing, and consultant packages.
Next steps are connecting the assistant to live scan task data, adding a secure model gateway, and generating PDF report sections from scan evidence.
For HackOnVibe, this AI assistant helps small teams move from scan output to remediation action.